<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/daniel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-04-30T20:51:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/daniel/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Ehouarn Le Faou | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Evolutionary biologist</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The History of Visual Communication</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/history-of-visual-communication" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The History of Visual Communication" />
      <published>2022-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2022-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/history-of-visual-communication</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history-of-visual-communication">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Design&lt;/strong&gt; is a mixed discipline between design and information-development which is concerned with how media intermission such as printed, crafted, electronic media or presentations communicate with people. A communication design approach is not only concerned with developing the message aside from the aesthetics in media, but also with creating new media channels to ensure the message reaches the target audience. Some designers use graphic design and communication design interchangeably due to overlapping skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication design can also refer to a systems-based approach, in which the totality of media and messages within a culture or organization are designed as a single integrated process rather than a series of discrete efforts. This is done through communication channels that aim to inform and attract the attention of the people you are focusing your skills on. Design skills must be tailored to fit to different cultures of people, while maintaining pleasurable visual design. These are all important pieces of information to add to a media communications kit to get the best results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/21.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Don’t design for everyone. It’s impossible. All you end up doing is designing something that makes everyone unhappy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication design seeks to attract, inspire, create desires and motivate the people to respond to messages, with a view to making a favorable impact to the bottom line of the commissioning body, which can be either to build a brand, move sales, or for humanitarian purposes. Its process involves strategic business thinking, using market research, creativity, and problem-solving. Communications designers translate ideas and information through a variety of media. Their particular talent lies not only in the traditional skills of the hand, but also in their ability to think strategically in design and marketing terms, in order to establish credibility through the communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term communication design is often used interchangeably with visual communication, but has an alternative broader meaning that includes auditory, vocal, touch and smell. Examples of communication design include information architecture, editing, typography, illustration, web design, animation, advertising, ambient media, visual identity design, performing arts, copywriting and professional writing skills applied in the creative industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The identification of self-esteem as a distinct psychological construct is thought to have its origins in the work of William James (1892). James identified multiple dimensions of the self, with two levels of hierarchy: processes of knowing (called the ‘I-self’) and the resulting knowledge about the today.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Design" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Communication Design is a mixed discipline between design and information-development which is concerned with how media intermission such as printed, crafted, electronic media or presentations communicate with people. A communication design approach is not only concerned with developing the message aside from the aesthetics in media, but also with creating new media channels to ensure the message reaches the target audience. Some designers use graphic design and communication design interchangeably due to overlapping skills.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">What Is Photography and What It Means To Me</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-photography-and-what-it-means-to-me" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Is Photography and What It Means To Me" />
      <published>2022-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-photography-and-what-it-means-to-me</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-is-photography-and-what-it-means-to-me">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photography&lt;/strong&gt; is the science, art and practice of creating durable images by recording light or other electromagnetic radiation, either electronically by means of an image sensor, or chemically by means of a light-sensitive material such as photographic film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, a lens is used to focus the light reflected or emitted from objects into a real image on the light-sensitive surface inside a camera during a timed exposure. With an electronic image sensor, this produces an electrical charge at each pixel, which is electronically processed and stored in a digital image file for subsequent display or processing. The result with photographic emulsion is an invisible latent image, which is later chemically “developed” into a visible image, either negative or positive depending on the purpose of the photographic material and the method of processing. A negative image on film is traditionally used to photographically create a positive image on a paper base, known as a print, either by using an enlarger or by contact printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photography is employed in many fields of science, manufacturing &lt;em&gt;(e.g. photolithography)&lt;/em&gt; and business, as well as its more direct uses for art, recreational purposes, hobby, and mass communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;film-photography&quot;&gt;Film photography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first flexible photographic roll film was marketed by George Eastman in 1885, but this original “film” was actually a coating on a paper base. As part of the processing, the image-bearing layer was stripped from the paper and transferred to a hardened gelatin support. The first transparent plastic roll film followed in 1889. It was made from highly flammable nitrocellulose (“celluloid”), now usually called “nitrate film”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/1.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although cellulose acetate or “safety film” had been introduced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastman_Kodak&quot;&gt;Kodak&lt;/a&gt; in 1908, at first it found only a few special applications as an alternative to the hazardous nitrate film, which had the advantages of being considerably tougher, slightly more transparent, and cheaper. The changeover was not completed for X-ray films until 1933, and although safety film was always used for 16 mm and 8 mm home movies, nitrate film remained standard for theatrical 35 mm motion pictures until it was finally discontinued in 1951.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Films remained the dominant form of photography until the early 21st century, when advances in digital photography made them largely obsolete. Although the 21st century is dominated by digital photography, film continues to be used by enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;black--white&quot;&gt;Black &amp;amp; White&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All photography was originally monochrome, or black-and-white. Even after color film was readily available, black-and-white photography continued to dominate for decades, due to its lower cost and its “classic” photographic look. The tones and contrast between light and dark areas define black-and-white photography. It is important to note that monochromatic pictures are not necessarily composed of pure blacks, whites, and intermediate shades of gray, but can involve shades of one particular hue depending on the process. The cyanotype process, for example, produces an image composed of blue tones. The albumen print process, first used more than 150 years ago, produces brownish tones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1428908200541-d395094cc816?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=6ba3e8f90dcd5a1188a4fa7fefc9df97#wide&quot; alt=&quot;A person running across the street on a rainy night&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@wirhabenzeit?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Dominik Schröder&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you photograph people in color, you photograph their clothes. But when you photograph people in Black and white, you photograph their souls!” &lt;cite&gt;― Ted Grant&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many photographers continue to produce some monochrome images, sometimes because of the established archival permanence of well-processed silver-halide-based materials. Some full-color digital images are processed using a variety of techniques to create black-and-white results, and some manufacturers produce digital cameras that exclusively shoot monochrome. Monochrome printing or electronic display can be used to salvage certain photographs taken in color which are unsatisfactory in their original form; sometimes when presented as black-and-white or single-color-toned images they are found to be more effective. Although color photography has long predominated, monochrome images are still produced, mostly for artistic reasons. Almost all digital cameras have an option to shoot in monochrome, and almost all image editing software can combine or selectively discard RGB color channels to produce a monochrome image from one shot in color.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Photography" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Photography is the science, art and practice of creating durable images by recording light or other electromagnetic radiation, either electronically by means of an image sensor, or chemically by means of a light-sensitive material such as photographic film.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Modern Graphic Design - Directions and Purpose</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/modern-graphic-design-directions-and-purpose" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Graphic Design - Directions and Purpose" />
      <published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/modern-graphic-design-directions-and-purpose</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/modern-graphic-design-directions-and-purpose">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A graphic designer&lt;/strong&gt; is a professional within the graphic design and graphic arts industry who assembles together images, typography, or motion graphics to create a piece of design. A graphic designer creates the graphics primarily for published, printed or electronic media, such as brochures (sometimes) and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are also sometimes responsible for typesetting, illustration, user interfaces, web design, or take a teaching position. A core responsibility of the designer’s job is to present information in a way that is both accessible and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/18.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I like it to be visually powerful, intellectually elegant, and above all, timeless.
&lt;cite&gt;Massimo Vignelli&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A degree or certificate from an accredited trade school is usually considered essential for a graphic design position. After a career history has been established, though, the graphic designer’s experience and number of years in the business are considered the primary qualifications. A portfolio, which is the primary method for demonstrating these qualifications, is usually required to be shown at job interviews, and is constantly developed throughout a designer’s career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice molecules can exhibit up to sixteen different phases (packing geometries) that depend on temperature and pressure. When water is cooled rapidly (quenching), up to three different types of amorphous ice can form depending on the history of its pressure and temperature. When cooled slowly correlated proton tunneling occurs below 20 K giving rise to macroscopic quantum phenomena. Virtually all the ice on Earth’s surface and in its atmosphere is of a hexagonal crystalline structure denoted as ice Ih (spoken as “ice one h”) with minute traces of cubic ice denoted as ice Ic. The most common phase transition to ice Ih occurs when liquid water is cooled below 0°C (273.15K, 32°F) at standard atmospheric pressure. It may also be deposited directly by water vapor, as happens in the formation of frost. The transition from ice to water is melting and from ice directly to water vapor is sublimation.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Design" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A graphic designer is a professional within the graphic design and graphic arts industry who assembles together images, typography, or motion graphics to create a piece of design. A graphic designer creates the graphics primarily for published, printed or electronic media, such as brochures (sometimes) and advertising.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Experience The Dramatic Landscape</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/experience-dramatic-landscape" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Experience The Dramatic Landscape" />
      <published>2018-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2018-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/experience-dramatic-landscape</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/experience-dramatic-landscape">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mount Everest&lt;/strong&gt;, also known in Nepal as Sagarmāthā and in Tibet as Chomolungma, is Earth’s highest mountain. It is located in the Mahalangur mountain range in Nepal. Its peak is 8,848 metres (29,029 ft) above sea level. It is not the furthest summit from the centre of the Earth. That honour goes to Mount Chimborazo, in the Andes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international border between China and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nepal&quot;&gt;Nepal&lt;/a&gt; runs across Everest’s precise summit point. Its massif includes neighbouring peaks Lhotse, 8,516 m (27,940 ft); Nuptse, 7,855 m (25,771 ft) and Changtse, 7,580 m (24,870 ft).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1856, the Great Trigonometrical Survey of India established the first published height of Everest, then known as Peak XV, at 29,002 ft (8,840 m). The current official height of 8,848 m (29,029 ft) as recognised by China and Nepal was established by a 1955 Indian survey and subsequently confirmed by a Chinese survey in 1975. In 1865, Everest was given its official English name by the Royal Geographical Society upon a recommendation by Andrew Waugh, the British Surveyor General of India. Waugh named the mountain after his predecessor in the post, Sir George Everest, arguing that there were many local names, against the opinion of Everest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Everest attracts many highly experienced mountaineers as well as capable climbers willing to hire professional guides. There are two main climbing routes, one approaching the summit from the southeast in Nepal (known as the standard route) and the other from the north in Tibet. While not posing substantial technical climbing challenges on the standard route, Everest presents dangers such as altitude sickness, weather, wind as well as significant objective hazards from avalanches and the Khumbu Icefall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/20.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recorded efforts to reach Everest’s summit were made by British mountaineers. With Nepal not allowing foreigners into the country at the time, the British made several attempts on the north ridge route from the Tibetan side. After the first reconnaissance expedition by the British in 1921 reached 7,000 m (22,970 ft) on the North Col, the 1922 expedition pushed the North ridge route up to 8,320 m (27,300 ft) marking the first time a human had climbed above 8,000 m (26,247 ft). Tragedy struck on the descent from the North col when seven porters were killed in an avalanche. The 1924 expedition resulted in the greatest mystery on Everest to this day: George Mallory and Andrew Irvine made a final summit attempt on June 8 but never returned, sparking debate as to whether they were the first to reach the top. They had been spotted high on the mountain that day but disappeared in the clouds, never to be seen again, until Mallory’s body was found in 1999 at 8,155 m (26,755 ft) on the North face. Tenzing Norgay and Edmund Hillary made the first official ascent of Everest in 1953 using the southeast ridge route. Tenzing had reached 8,595 m (28,199 ft) the previous year as a member of the 1952 Swiss expedition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The British were forced to continue their observations from Terai, a region south of Nepal which is parallel to the Himalayas. Conditions in Terai were difficult because of torrential rains and malaria. Three survey officers died from malaria while two others had to retire because of failing health.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Photography" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Mount Everest, also known in Nepal as Sagarmāthā and in Tibet as Chomolungma, is Earth’s highest mountain. It is located in the Mahalangur mountain range in Nepal. Its peak is 8,848 metres (29,029 ft) above sea level. It is not the furthest summit from the centre of the Earth. That honour goes to Mount Chimborazo, in the Andes.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">React.js Conferences to Attend in 2019</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/react-conferences-to-attend-in-2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="React.js Conferences to Attend in 2019" />
      <published>2018-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2018-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/react-conferences-to-attend-in-2018</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/react-conferences-to-attend-in-2018">&lt;p&gt;Conferences are a perfect way to make friends and learn from experts. Here are some React conferences to look forward to in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you’ll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You’ll also notice that there’s a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let’s run you through some of the basics. You’ll want to make sure you’re editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we’ve used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;formatting-text&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you’re well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inserting-images&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they’re prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-lists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make an omelette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-quotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good excerpt in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might’ve seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they’ll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividing-things-up&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleek divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Development" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Conferences are a perfect way to make friends and learn from experts. Here are some React conferences to look forward to in 2018.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/advanced-markdown-tips" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" />
      <published>2018-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2018-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/advanced-markdown-tips</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/advanced-markdown-tips">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with Markdown in Jekyll, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-footnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Jekyll" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with Markdown in Jekyll, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with it!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Week With the Apple Watch</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/a-week-with-the-apple-watch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Week With the Apple Watch" />
      <published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/a-week-with-the-apple-watch</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-week-with-the-apple-watch">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch&lt;/strong&gt; is a smartwatch developed by Apple Inc. It incorporates fitness tracking and health-oriented capabilities as well as integration with iOS and other Apple products and services. The device is available in four variants: Apple Watch Sport, Apple Watch, Apple Watch Hermès, and Apple Watch Edition. The Watch is distinguished by different combinations of cases and first or third party interchangeable bands. Apple Watch relies on a wirelessly connected iPhone to perform many of its default functions such as calling and texting. It is compatible with the iPhone 5 or later models running iOS 8.2 or later, through the use of Bluetooth or Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announced by Tim Cook on September 9, 2014, the device was available for pre-order on April 10 and began shipping on April 24, 2015. The Apple Watch quickly became the best-selling wearable device, with the shipment of 4.2 million smartwatches in the second quarter of 2015, according to analyst firm Canalys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You can only do so many things great, and you should cast aside everything else.” ― Tim Cook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumors surrounded an Apple-developed wearable back as far as 2011, which conceptualized the device as a variation of the iPod that would curve around the user’s wrist, and feature Siri integration. On February 10, 2013, both The New York Times and The Wall Street Journal reported that Apple was beginning to develop an iOS-based smartwatch with a curved display. On February 12, 2013, Bloomberg reported that Apple’s smartwatch project was “beyond the experimentation phase in its development”, and had a team of at least 100 designers were working on the project. Further reports in March 2013 indicated that Apple planned to release the device by the end of the year. In July 2013, Financial Times reported that Apple had begun hiring more employees to work on the smartwatch, and that it was targeting a possible retail release in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unveiling--release&quot;&gt;Unveiling &amp;amp; Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2014, Apple CEO Tim Cook told The Wall Street Journal that the company was planning to launch new product categories that year, but did not reveal any specifics. In June 2014, Reuters reported that production was expected to begin in July for a release in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch was first unveiled after a classic and ever infamous “We do have ‘one more thing’…” slide, which heard enormous applause, on September 9, 2014 during a press event which also saw the introduction of the iPhone 6. After the reveal video, the auditorium erupted with applause while Tim Cook rolled back his sleeve, revealing an Apple Watch on his wrist. Speaking about the device, Apple CEO Tim Cook explained that Apple Watch was “a new, intimate way to communicate from your wrist, and a comprehensive health and fitness device.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Tips" />
      
        <category term="Minimal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The Apple Watch is a smartwatch developed by Apple Inc. It incorporates fitness tracking and health-oriented capabilities as well as integration with iOS and other Apple products and services. The device is available in four variants: Apple Watch Sport, Apple Watch, Apple Watch Hermès, and Apple Watch Edition. The Watch is distinguished by different combinations of cases and first or third party interchangeable bands. Apple Watch relies on a wirelessly connected iPhone to perform many of its default functions such as calling and texting. It is compatible with the iPhone 5 or later models running iOS 8.2 or later, through the use of Bluetooth or Wi-Fi.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
