<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ehouarn Le Faou</title>
    <description>Evolutionary biologist</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 20:51:35 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 20:51:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of Visual Communication</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Design&lt;/strong&gt; is a mixed discipline between design and information-development which is concerned with how media intermission such as printed, crafted, electronic media or presentations communicate with people. A communication design approach is not only concerned with developing the message aside from the aesthetics in media, but also with creating new media channels to ensure the message reaches the target audience. Some designers use graphic design and communication design interchangeably due to overlapping skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication design can also refer to a systems-based approach, in which the totality of media and messages within a culture or organization are designed as a single integrated process rather than a series of discrete efforts. This is done through communication channels that aim to inform and attract the attention of the people you are focusing your skills on. Design skills must be tailored to fit to different cultures of people, while maintaining pleasurable visual design. These are all important pieces of information to add to a media communications kit to get the best results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/21.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Don’t design for everyone. It’s impossible. All you end up doing is designing something that makes everyone unhappy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication design seeks to attract, inspire, create desires and motivate the people to respond to messages, with a view to making a favorable impact to the bottom line of the commissioning body, which can be either to build a brand, move sales, or for humanitarian purposes. Its process involves strategic business thinking, using market research, creativity, and problem-solving. Communications designers translate ideas and information through a variety of media. Their particular talent lies not only in the traditional skills of the hand, but also in their ability to think strategically in design and marketing terms, in order to establish credibility through the communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term communication design is often used interchangeably with visual communication, but has an alternative broader meaning that includes auditory, vocal, touch and smell. Examples of communication design include information architecture, editing, typography, illustration, web design, animation, advertising, ambient media, visual identity design, performing arts, copywriting and professional writing skills applied in the creative industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The identification of self-esteem as a distinct psychological construct is thought to have its origins in the work of William James (1892). James identified multiple dimensions of the self, with two levels of hierarchy: processes of knowing (called the ‘I-self’) and the resulting knowledge about the today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/history-of-visual-communication</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/history-of-visual-communication</guid>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Photography and What It Means To Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photography&lt;/strong&gt; is the science, art and practice of creating durable images by recording light or other electromagnetic radiation, either electronically by means of an image sensor, or chemically by means of a light-sensitive material such as photographic film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, a lens is used to focus the light reflected or emitted from objects into a real image on the light-sensitive surface inside a camera during a timed exposure. With an electronic image sensor, this produces an electrical charge at each pixel, which is electronically processed and stored in a digital image file for subsequent display or processing. The result with photographic emulsion is an invisible latent image, which is later chemically “developed” into a visible image, either negative or positive depending on the purpose of the photographic material and the method of processing. A negative image on film is traditionally used to photographically create a positive image on a paper base, known as a print, either by using an enlarger or by contact printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photography is employed in many fields of science, manufacturing &lt;em&gt;(e.g. photolithography)&lt;/em&gt; and business, as well as its more direct uses for art, recreational purposes, hobby, and mass communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;film-photography&quot;&gt;Film photography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first flexible photographic roll film was marketed by George Eastman in 1885, but this original “film” was actually a coating on a paper base. As part of the processing, the image-bearing layer was stripped from the paper and transferred to a hardened gelatin support. The first transparent plastic roll film followed in 1889. It was made from highly flammable nitrocellulose (“celluloid”), now usually called “nitrate film”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/1.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although cellulose acetate or “safety film” had been introduced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastman_Kodak&quot;&gt;Kodak&lt;/a&gt; in 1908, at first it found only a few special applications as an alternative to the hazardous nitrate film, which had the advantages of being considerably tougher, slightly more transparent, and cheaper. The changeover was not completed for X-ray films until 1933, and although safety film was always used for 16 mm and 8 mm home movies, nitrate film remained standard for theatrical 35 mm motion pictures until it was finally discontinued in 1951.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Films remained the dominant form of photography until the early 21st century, when advances in digital photography made them largely obsolete. Although the 21st century is dominated by digital photography, film continues to be used by enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;black--white&quot;&gt;Black &amp;amp; White&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All photography was originally monochrome, or black-and-white. Even after color film was readily available, black-and-white photography continued to dominate for decades, due to its lower cost and its “classic” photographic look. The tones and contrast between light and dark areas define black-and-white photography. It is important to note that monochromatic pictures are not necessarily composed of pure blacks, whites, and intermediate shades of gray, but can involve shades of one particular hue depending on the process. The cyanotype process, for example, produces an image composed of blue tones. The albumen print process, first used more than 150 years ago, produces brownish tones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1428908200541-d395094cc816?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=6ba3e8f90dcd5a1188a4fa7fefc9df97#wide&quot; alt=&quot;A person running across the street on a rainy night&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@wirhabenzeit?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Dominik Schröder&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you photograph people in color, you photograph their clothes. But when you photograph people in Black and white, you photograph their souls!” &lt;cite&gt;― Ted Grant&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many photographers continue to produce some monochrome images, sometimes because of the established archival permanence of well-processed silver-halide-based materials. Some full-color digital images are processed using a variety of techniques to create black-and-white results, and some manufacturers produce digital cameras that exclusively shoot monochrome. Monochrome printing or electronic display can be used to salvage certain photographs taken in color which are unsatisfactory in their original form; sometimes when presented as black-and-white or single-color-toned images they are found to be more effective. Although color photography has long predominated, monochrome images are still produced, mostly for artistic reasons. Almost all digital cameras have an option to shoot in monochrome, and almost all image editing software can combine or selectively discard RGB color channels to produce a monochrome image from one shot in color.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-photography-and-what-it-means-to-me</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-photography-and-what-it-means-to-me</guid>
        
        <category>Photography</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Modern Graphic Design - Directions and Purpose</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A graphic designer&lt;/strong&gt; is a professional within the graphic design and graphic arts industry who assembles together images, typography, or motion graphics to create a piece of design. A graphic designer creates the graphics primarily for published, printed or electronic media, such as brochures (sometimes) and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are also sometimes responsible for typesetting, illustration, user interfaces, web design, or take a teaching position. A core responsibility of the designer’s job is to present information in a way that is both accessible and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/18.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I like it to be visually powerful, intellectually elegant, and above all, timeless.
&lt;cite&gt;Massimo Vignelli&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A degree or certificate from an accredited trade school is usually considered essential for a graphic design position. After a career history has been established, though, the graphic designer’s experience and number of years in the business are considered the primary qualifications. A portfolio, which is the primary method for demonstrating these qualifications, is usually required to be shown at job interviews, and is constantly developed throughout a designer’s career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice molecules can exhibit up to sixteen different phases (packing geometries) that depend on temperature and pressure. When water is cooled rapidly (quenching), up to three different types of amorphous ice can form depending on the history of its pressure and temperature. When cooled slowly correlated proton tunneling occurs below 20 K giving rise to macroscopic quantum phenomena. Virtually all the ice on Earth’s surface and in its atmosphere is of a hexagonal crystalline structure denoted as ice Ih (spoken as “ice one h”) with minute traces of cubic ice denoted as ice Ic. The most common phase transition to ice Ih occurs when liquid water is cooled below 0°C (273.15K, 32°F) at standard atmospheric pressure. It may also be deposited directly by water vapor, as happens in the formation of frost. The transition from ice to water is melting and from ice directly to water vapor is sublimation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/modern-graphic-design-directions-and-purpose</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/modern-graphic-design-directions-and-purpose</guid>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Start Learning Blockchain Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A blockchain, originally block chain, is a continuously growing list of records, called blocks, which are linked and secured using cryptography. Each block typically contains a hash pointer as a link to a previous block, a timestamp and transaction data. By design, a blockchain is inherently resistant to modification of the data. It is &lt;em&gt;“an open, distributed ledger that can record transactions between two parties efficiently and in a verifiable and permanent way”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For use as a distributed ledger, a blockchain is typically managed by a peer-to-peer network collectively adhering to a protocol for validating new blocks. Once recorded, the data in any given block cannot be altered retroactively without the alteration of all subsequent blocks, which requires collusion of the network majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains are secure by design and are an example of a distributed computing system with high Byzantine fault tolerance. Decentralized consensus has therefore been achieved with a blockchain. This makes blockchains potentially suitable for the recording of events, medical records, and other records management activities, such as identity management, transaction processing, documenting provenance, food traceability or voting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-blocks-highlighted-with-prismjs&quot;&gt;Code blocks, highlighted with &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/index.html&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markup&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; /&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Prism&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;style.css&quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;div class=&quot;intro&quot; data-src=&quot;templates/header-main.html&quot; data-type=&quot;text/html&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;ul id=&quot;features&quot;&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Dead simple&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Light as a feather&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Extensible&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;section id=&quot;features-full&quot; class=&quot;language-markup&quot;&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Full list of features&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Only 2KB&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; minified &amp;amp; gzipped (core). Each language definition adds roughly 300-500 bytes.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Very easy to extend without modifying the code, due to Prism’s &amp;lt;a href=&quot;#plugins&quot;&amp;gt;plugin architecture&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Multiple hooks are scattered throughout the source.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Very easy to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;extending.html#language-definitions&quot;&amp;gt;define new languages&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Only thing you need is a good understanding of regular expressions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;footer data-src=&quot;templates/footer.html&quot; data-type=&quot;text/html&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;var Token = _.Token = function(type, content, alias, matchedStr, greedy) {
	this.type = type;
	this.content = content;
	this.alias = alias;
	// Copy of the full string this token was created from
	this.length = (matchedStr || &quot;&quot;).length|0;
	this.greedy = !!greedy;
};&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;@import url(http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Arvo);

/* Styles */

body {
	font: 100%/1.5 Questrial, sans-serif;
	tab-size: 4;
	hyphens: auto;
}

a {
	color: inherit;
}

section h1 {
	font-size: 250%;
}

section h1,
#features li strong,
header h2,
footer p {
	font: 100% Rockwell, Arvo, serif;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first blockchain was conceptualized in 2008 by an anonymous person or group known as Satoshi Nakamoto and implemented in 2009 as a core component of bitcoin where it serves as the public ledger for all transactions. The invention of the blockchain for bitcoin made it the first digital currency to solve the double spending problem without the need of a trusted authority or central server. The bitcoin design has been the inspiration for other applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first work on a cryptographically secured chain of blocks was described in 1991 by Stuart Haber and W. Scott Stornetta. In 1992, Bayer, Haber and Stornetta incorporated Merkle trees to the design, which improved its efficiency by allowing several documents to be collected into one block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1451187580459-43490279c0fa?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ&amp;amp;s=163e3ea37d2c0fda3f586d5552752f59#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”Bitcoin is the beginning of something great: a currency without a government, something necessary and imperative.” &lt;cite&gt;– Peter Thiel, Co-Founder of PayPal –&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first blockchain was conceptualised by an anonymous person or group known as Satoshi Nakamoto in 2008. It was implemented the following year as a core component of the digital currency bitcoin, where it serves as the public ledger for all transactions on the network. By using a blockchain, bitcoin became the first digital currency to solve the double spending problem without requiring a trusted administrator and has been the inspiration for many additional applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structure&quot;&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is a decentralized and distributed digital ledger that is used to record transactions across many computers so that the record cannot be altered retroactively without the alteration of all subsequent blocks and the collusion of the network. This allows the participants to verify and audit transactions inexpensively. A blockchain database is managed autonomously using a peer-to-peer network and a distributed timestamping server. They are authenticated by mass collaboration powered by collective self-interests. The result is a robust workflow where participants’ uncertainty regarding data security is marginal. The use of a blockchain removes the characteristic of infinite reproducibility from a digital asset. It confirms that each unit of value was transferred only once, solving the long-standing problem of double spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains have been described as a value-exchange protocol. This blockchain-based exchange of value can be completed more quickly, more safely and more cheaply than with traditional systems. A blockchain can assign title rights because it provides a record that compels offer and acceptance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain&quot;&gt;(Source)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-start-learning-blockchain-development</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-start-learning-blockchain-development</guid>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Development</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cutting Edge Architecture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This beautiful rough concrete house located in the small town of &lt;strong&gt;Besalu in the Ayora&lt;/strong&gt;, Valencia region, Spain, has been designed by Fran Silvestre, a talented architectural firm from Spain. Set in a sloping plain, the House allows its concrete exterior to show through without overwhelming the minimal interior. The house is hexagonal, allowing for a room layout that lends itself to eye-catching reveals. Warm wood floors and cabinets pair with white walls and exposed grey concrete to give the interior a cozy yet distinctly modern feel, while abundant windows let in plenty of natural light while providing views to the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way the house is conceived as a piece deposited on the ground, engaging the unevenness. A piece constructed in the same white lime, with the same primacy of the massif over the span, that takes advantage of the edge of the lot to arrange its holes and to integrate in the fragmentation of the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interior space of the dwelling is articulated through the void in which is located the nucleus of communication arranged parallel to the cut of the mountain, without touching it. On the ground floor are the garage and the cellar, on this is arranged a volume of two floors with four rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is this visually striking architectural design, but it’s beautifully considered and practical for those who will experience this school on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“To expect the unexpected shows a thoroughly modern intellect.” &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London is a leading global city, with strengths in the arts, commerce, education, entertainment, fashion, finance, healthcare, media, professional services, research and development, tourism, and transport all contributing to its prominence. It is one of the world’s leading financial centres and has the fifth-or sixth-largest metropolitan area GDP in the world depending on measurement. London is a world cultural capital. It is the world’s most-visited city as measured by international arrivals and has the world’s largest city airport system measured by passenger traffic. London is the world’s leading investment destination, hosting more international retailers and ultra high-net-worth individuals than any other city. London’s 43 universities form the largest concentration of higher education institutes in Europe, and a 2014 report placed it first in the world university rankings. According to the report London also ranks first in the world in software, multimedia development and design, and shares first position in technology readiness. In 2012, London became the first city to host the modern &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summer_Olympic_Games&quot;&gt;Summer Olympic Games three times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1509440400926-95da53da5dc0?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=7918f34cc00f122a16cb75b2378eefab#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;alignleft&quot;&gt;“Architecture should speak of its time and place, but yearn for timelessness.” &lt;cite&gt;― Frank Gehry&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London has a diverse range of peoples and cultures, and more than 300 languages are spoken within Greater London. The Greater London Authority estimated its population to be 8.63 million in 2015, the largest of any municipality in the European Union, and accounting for 12.5 percent of the UK population. London’s urban area is the second most populous in the EU, after Paris, with 9,787,426 inhabitants according to the 2011 census. The city’s metropolitan area is one of the most populous in Europe with 13,879,757 inhabitants, while the Greater London Authority states the population of the city-region (covering a large part of south east England) as 22.7 million. London was the world’s most populous city from around 1831 to 1925.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London contains four World Heritage Sites: the Tower of London; Kew Gardens; the site comprising the Palace of Westminster, Westminster Abbey, and St Margaret’s Church; and the historic settlement of Greenwich (in which the Royal Observatory, Greenwich marks the Prime Meridian, 0° longitude, and GMT). Other famous landmarks include Buckingham Palace, the London Eye, Piccadilly Circus, St Paul’s Cathedral, Tower Bridge, Trafalgar Square, and The Shard. London is home to numerous museums, galleries, libraries, sporting events and other cultural institutions, including the British Museum, National Gallery, Tate Modern, British Library and 40 West End theatres. The London Underground is the oldest underground railway network in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;museum-of-london&quot;&gt;Museum of London&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1484626753559-5fa3ea273ae8?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=c21ca0246d75ba185a49d687683dc08c#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@dnevozhai?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Denys Nevozhai&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Museum of London documents the history of London from prehistoric to modern times. The museum is located on London Wall, close to the Barbican Centre as part of the striking Barbican complex of buildings created in the 1960s and 1970s as an innovative approach to re-development within a bomb-damaged area of the City of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a few minutes’ walk north of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Paul%27s_Cathedral&quot;&gt;St Paul’s Cathedral&lt;/a&gt;, overlooking the remains of the Roman city wall and on the edge of the oldest part of London, now its main financial district. It is primarily concerned with the social history of London and its inhabitants throughout time. The museum is jointly controlled and funded by the City of London Corporation and the Greater London Authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2015, the museum announced plans to move from its Barbican site to nearby Smithfield Market. The move, contingent upon raising an estimated £70 million, is planned to be complete by 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amalgamation of the collections previously held by the City Corporation at the Guildhall Museum and of the London Museum, which was located in Kensington Palace was agreed in 1964. The Museum of London Act, allowing for the merger, was passed in the following year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum was opened in December 1976 as part of the Barbican Estate, The architects were Philip Powell and Hidalgo Moya, who adopted an innovative approach to museum design, whereby the galleries were laid out so that there was only one route through the museum – from the prehistoric period to the modern galleries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum comprises a series of chronological galleries containing original artefacts, models, pictures and diagrams, with a strong emphasis on archaeological discoveries, the built city, urban development and London’s social and cultural life, with interactive displays and activities for all ages. Fragments of the Roman London Wall can be seen just outside the museum. The prehistoric gallery, “London Before London” and the “Medieval London” gallery have already been updated, and in 2010 a refurbished gallery on &lt;em&gt;“War, Plague and Fire”&lt;/em&gt; opened, covering the period of the English Civil War and the Great Fire of London.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-cutting-edge-architecture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-cutting-edge-architecture</guid>
        
        <category>Architecture</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Experience The Dramatic Landscape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mount Everest&lt;/strong&gt;, also known in Nepal as Sagarmāthā and in Tibet as Chomolungma, is Earth’s highest mountain. It is located in the Mahalangur mountain range in Nepal. Its peak is 8,848 metres (29,029 ft) above sea level. It is not the furthest summit from the centre of the Earth. That honour goes to Mount Chimborazo, in the Andes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international border between China and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nepal&quot;&gt;Nepal&lt;/a&gt; runs across Everest’s precise summit point. Its massif includes neighbouring peaks Lhotse, 8,516 m (27,940 ft); Nuptse, 7,855 m (25,771 ft) and Changtse, 7,580 m (24,870 ft).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1856, the Great Trigonometrical Survey of India established the first published height of Everest, then known as Peak XV, at 29,002 ft (8,840 m). The current official height of 8,848 m (29,029 ft) as recognised by China and Nepal was established by a 1955 Indian survey and subsequently confirmed by a Chinese survey in 1975. In 1865, Everest was given its official English name by the Royal Geographical Society upon a recommendation by Andrew Waugh, the British Surveyor General of India. Waugh named the mountain after his predecessor in the post, Sir George Everest, arguing that there were many local names, against the opinion of Everest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Everest attracts many highly experienced mountaineers as well as capable climbers willing to hire professional guides. There are two main climbing routes, one approaching the summit from the southeast in Nepal (known as the standard route) and the other from the north in Tibet. While not posing substantial technical climbing challenges on the standard route, Everest presents dangers such as altitude sickness, weather, wind as well as significant objective hazards from avalanches and the Khumbu Icefall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/20.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first recorded efforts to reach Everest’s summit were made by British mountaineers. With Nepal not allowing foreigners into the country at the time, the British made several attempts on the north ridge route from the Tibetan side. After the first reconnaissance expedition by the British in 1921 reached 7,000 m (22,970 ft) on the North Col, the 1922 expedition pushed the North ridge route up to 8,320 m (27,300 ft) marking the first time a human had climbed above 8,000 m (26,247 ft). Tragedy struck on the descent from the North col when seven porters were killed in an avalanche. The 1924 expedition resulted in the greatest mystery on Everest to this day: George Mallory and Andrew Irvine made a final summit attempt on June 8 but never returned, sparking debate as to whether they were the first to reach the top. They had been spotted high on the mountain that day but disappeared in the clouds, never to be seen again, until Mallory’s body was found in 1999 at 8,155 m (26,755 ft) on the North face. Tenzing Norgay and Edmund Hillary made the first official ascent of Everest in 1953 using the southeast ridge route. Tenzing had reached 8,595 m (28,199 ft) the previous year as a member of the 1952 Swiss expedition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The British were forced to continue their observations from Terai, a region south of Nepal which is parallel to the Himalayas. Conditions in Terai were difficult because of torrential rains and malaria. Three survey officers died from malaria while two others had to retire because of failing health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience-dramatic-landscape</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience-dramatic-landscape</guid>
        
        <category>Photography</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seven Things That Will Make Or Break Fusion Festival</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fusion Festival&lt;/strong&gt; is a music and arts festival with a countercultural character. It takes place at a former military airport called Müritz Airpark in Lärz, Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, in northeastern &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/a&gt;. The festival name is often depicted in Cyrillic letters as Фузион, but pronounced like the English word fusion [‘fjuʒən].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The annual festival was started by the Kulturkosmos organisation in 1997. It lasts four to six days, usually at the end of June. In 2015, the Fusion is scheduled to take place from June 25 - 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;alignright&quot;&gt;“One good thing about music, when it hits you, you feel no pain.”
&lt;cite&gt;― Bob Marley&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different musical styles are represented at the festival, but the line up is not released beforehand. Mostly electronic music is present, but there is no stylistic restriction for the various live music acts, and the festival attendees may bring their own instruments. The festival also holds its own film festival and features different scales of art installations. Attendees may bring their own art and appear in artistic costumes. Only vegetarian food is sold at the festival grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The festival gears to create a Temporary Autonomous Zone and a transformational environment. Due to its avantgardistic attitude and the variety of art, the Fusion Festival has been described by organizers as a European Burning Man, although it is not an official regional Burn. It is also compared to the Glastonbury Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1492684223066-81342ee5ff30?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=e778bd090eca235b5999595ae1223575#wide&quot; alt=&quot;Confetti flying over the attendees of a concert at Dockville Festival&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@pabloheimplatz?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Pablo Heimplatz&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=api-credit&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concept&quot;&gt;Concept&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fusion Festival combines all styles of the underground electronic music scene and various other styles, sometimes depending on the attendees who choose to play their own music. It is described as a space people go to free their minds from their everyday lives, jobs, studies and other responsibilities. It is the result of the search for an alternative through music, to the system “people are forced to live in”. People go to the Fusion to experience a different way of socializing and living, where experiencing one another freely, sharing love for music and art connects different scenes and minds. It is a clothing-optional event. Art installations include performance arts, static artworks, sculptures, art cars and various other forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fusion Festival began in 1997 near the city of Lärz in north-eastern Germany, about 160 km from Berlin and 230 km from Hamburg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;festival-site&quot;&gt;Festival Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The location is on the original grass-covered grounds of a disused military airfield (at 53°20′48.11″N 12°44′23.25″E for the 234-hectare area central field) about 4.5 km (2.25 miles) due north of the modern Rechlin-Lärz Airfield facility. The site was first acquired by the German Empire in 1916 as an aviation research and training ground, opening the facility for use by the Luftstreitkräfte in August 1918. After the establishment of the Luftwaffe in 1935, the field served as the Erprobungsstelle Rechlin central military aircraft test facility of the Third Reich through early 1945, and it was captured by the Soviet Red Army on May 2, 1945, for use by the VVS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are grass-covered concrete hangars (actual bunkers) from that time that were used for Soviet fighter aircraft (hence the Cyrillic transliteration of the festival name and various stages, as many Cyrillic inscriptions were still present on the site). The airfield was reopened for civilian use in 1994 and sold to the Müritz Airpark Group in 2010. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fusion_Festival&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/six-things-that-will-make-or-break-fusion-festival</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/six-things-that-will-make-or-break-fusion-festival</guid>
        
        <category>Music</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages &amp; Disadvantages of Working from Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A work at home parent is an entrepreneur who works from home and integrates parenting into his or her business activities. They are sometimes referred to as a WAHM (work at home mom) or a WAHD (work at home dad).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs choose to run businesses from home for a variety of reasons, including lower business expenses, personal health limitations, eliminating commuting, or in order to have a more flexible schedule. This flexibility can give an entrepreneur more options when planning tasks, business and non-business, including parenting duties. While some home-based entrepreneurs opt for childcare outside the home,[1] others integrate child rearing into their work day and workspace. The latter are considered work-at-home parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many WAHPs start home-based businesses in order to care for their children while still creating income. The desire to care for one’s own children, the incompatibility of a 9-to-5 work day with school hours or sick days, and the expense of childcare prompt many parents to change or leave their jobs in the workforce to be available to their children. Many WAHPs build a business schedule that can be integrated with their parenting duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;types-of-work&quot;&gt;Types Of Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common types of work found in work-at-home schemes include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stuffing envelopes. The victim sees a flyer advertising a job stuffing envelopes, with “up to 1,000 envelopes a week that you can stuff… with postage and address already affixed!”, offering a payment of $1–2 per envelope. To apply for the job, the victim is required to send a self-addressed stamped envelope for information and a small processing fee. In return, the victim is sent a template for the flyer they had originally seen; the envelopes they stuff are from other people who answer the flyer, and the payment is the processing fee.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assembly of items of some type, such as crafts, jewellery or medical equipment. The worker is required to pay up front for materials and construction kits, and when they attempt to sell the finished products back to the scheme’s organiser, they are told that the products “don’t meet our specifications”, leaving the worker with assembled products and no buyer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Processing medical claims. The worker pays several hundred dollars for medical billing software, but will later discover that most medical clinics process their own bills, outsource their billing to established firms rather than individuals, or have stricter requirements than the purchased software can provide.
Forum spamming. Usually advertised as some variant of “email processing”, the worker is simply given instructions on spamming online forums, and told they can make money by selling these same instructions online.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sales of a product or service that is difficult or impossible to sell. This is often done in the form of a pyramid scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some adverts offer legitimate forms of work that really do exist, but exaggerate the salary and understate the effort that will have to be put into the job, or exaggerate the amount of work that will be available. Many such ads do not even specify the type of work that will be performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some similar schemes do not advertise work that would be performed at home, but may instead offer occasional, sporadic work away from home for large payments, paired with a lot of free time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/working-from-home</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/working-from-home</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>React.js Conferences to Attend in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Conferences are a perfect way to make friends and learn from experts. Here are some React conferences to look forward to in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you’ll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You’ll also notice that there’s a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let’s run you through some of the basics. You’ll want to make sure you’re editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we’ve used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;formatting-text&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you’re well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inserting-images&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they’re prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-lists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make an omelette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-quotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good excerpt in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might’ve seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they’ll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividing-things-up&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleek divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/react-conferences-to-attend-in-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/react-conferences-to-attend-in-2018</guid>
        
        <category>Development</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Options for creating a new site with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new &amp;lt;PATH&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; installs a new Jekyll site at the path specified (relative to current directory). In this case, Jekyll will be installed in a directory called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myblog&lt;/code&gt;. Here are some additional details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To install the Jekyll site into the directory you’re currently in, run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new&lt;/code&gt; . If the existing directory isn’t empty, you can pass the –force option with jekyll new . –force.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new&lt;/code&gt; automatically initiates &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; to install the dependencies required. (If you don’t want Bundler to install the gems, use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new myblog --skip-bundle&lt;/code&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default, the Jekyll site installed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new&lt;/code&gt; uses a gem-based theme called Minima. With gem-based themes, some of the directories and files are stored in the theme-gem, hidden from your immediate view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We recommend setting up Jekyll with a gem-based theme but if you want to start with a blank slate, use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new myblog --blank&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To learn about other parameters you can include with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new&lt;/code&gt;, type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll new --help&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/options-for-creating-new-site-with-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/options-for-creating-new-site-with-jekyll</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Development</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
